Watchmen: Chapter I is a animation, drama, science
fiction film directed by Brandon Vietti.
In 1985, the murder of a government-sponsored superhero draws his outlawed colleagues out of retirement
and into a mystery that threatens to upend their personal lives and the world itself.
Adrian Veidt / Ozymandias / Minister / Benny
Anger (voice), played by Troy Baker.
Sally Jupiter / Silk Spectre / TV Broadcaster
(voice), played by Adrienne Barbeau.
Captain Metropolis / Forbes / American Newscaster
(voice), played by Corey Burton.
Jonathan Osterman / Dr. Manhattan / Father (voice), played by Michael Cerveris.
Edgar Jacobi / Moloch / British Newscaster /
Photographer #1 (voice), played by Jeffrey Combs.
Female Citizen #2 / Spanish Newscaster (voice), played by Grey DeLisle.
Watchmen is a 2024 American adult animated two-part superhero
film directed by Brandon Vietti and written by J.
Michael Straczynski.
It stars an ensemble cast including Matthew Rhys, Katee Sackhoff, Titus
Welliver, Troy Baker, Adrienne Barbeau, and Michael Cerveris.
Chapter I is the 57th film, and Chapter II is the 58th film of the DC
Universe Animated Original Movies, and produced by Warner Bros.
Animation, Paramount Pictures, and DC
Entertainment, and distributed by Warner Bros.
Home Entertainment in North America and Paramount Home Entertainment elsewhere.
The film is based on the DC Comics limited series of the same name co-created and illustrated by Dave Gibbons, with
co-creator and author Alan Moore choosing to remain uncredited here for his work on the source material.
Set in an alternate 1985, the film follows a group of outlawed and retired superheroes
who investigate a conspiracy following the murder of one of their own.
Gibbons served as a consulting producer on the film.
Animation for the film was provided by Studio Mir.
The first part (titled Watchmen Chapter I) was released on August 13, 2024, while the
second part (titled Watchmen Chapter II) was released on November 26, 2024.
The film explores themes of nuclear war, secret identity,
retirement, conspiracy, alternate history.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.